Hi, welcome back.
欢迎回来
So now I sm interested in how you as a Tableau professional actually
现在我想知道 作为 Tableau 专业人士
start exploring a dataset.
你是如何开始探索数据集的
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's a great question.
—-问的好
And the fun thing about Tableau is that there are 1 million and
对于 Tableau 你可以采用
1 ways to explore data.
无数种方式探索数据
You can start with a question that you have and
你可以先提个问题
then try to answer that question in the data.
然后通过数据回答问题
Or you can start just by looking at the dimensions and
或者查看维度和测量结果
measures that you have and dragging those out onto the canvas and
然后将这些维度和测量结果拖到画布上
changing things around and changing the aggregation and starting to explore.
改动各个部分 更改集合 然后开始探索
And everyone has a different process.
每个人都会采用不同的流程
You can invent your own process.
你可以发明自己的流程
I often invent new processes.
我经常会发明新的流程
But one of the first things that I usually do is I take a look at the data
但是我经常一开始会看看要处理的数据
that I'm working with, because often it wasn't data that I personally collected.
因为通常这些数据不是我收集的
In this case, I've brought a dataset that the UN collected on refugee data.
这是一个联合国收集的难民数据集
So, we're looking at asylum seekers, where they came from,
我们查看的是避难者数据 他们来自何处
where they ended up, when they ended up in those countries.
他们留在了哪里 何时到达这些国家/地区
And I've already taken a step to clean up the data,
我已经对数据进行了清理
often that's a necessary step before you start visualizing it.
通常在开始可视化数据之前 有必要执行这一步
And in this case it was really easy, I just checked this check
这里非常简单 我只选中了这个复选框
box to clean it with our data interpreter and that took away a few
用我们的数据解析器对数据进行清理
rows in the beginning that weren't related to the rest of the dataset.
这样就将开头几行数据清理掉了 因为它们与数据集的其他部分关系不大
So then I'm going to open up a sheet and I'm going to start asking questions.
然后我将打开一个表格 开始提出问题
So one of the things that I want to know is how many
我想知道
people are in this dataset, right?
这个数据集中有多少人
How many people are we talking about here?
我们讨论的是多少人
So I'm going to drag this over onto the canvas and
我将这个拖到画布上
I can see that we're talking about a bit over 8 million asylum seekers.
可以看出难民为 800 万以上
Okay, so that's interesting.
有意思
Now I want to know where did these people come from and so
现在我想知道这些人来自何处
I'm going to drag their origin onto the columns.
所以将“Origin”拖到“Columns”上
Now this is a little bit difficult for me to see.
现在比较难以观察
It would be helpful if I could rotate it.
如果能旋转下 效果会更好
So I'm going to swap the axes here and then I'm going to sort the data.
交换坐标轴并对数据排序
And now I can start to see a story.
现在可以看清规律了
And I can start to see where these asylum seekers originated.
可以看出这些难民来自哪里
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's interesting.
—-不错
So, now at this point how would you say you use filters to
现在你会如何使用过滤器
keep digging in to the data?
继续探索这些数据？
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's a great question.
—-问的好
So Tableau makes it really easy to narrow down your data and drill in and
Tableau 使我们能非常轻松地缩小数据范围
understand the data from different perspectives.
从不同的角度查看数据
So in this case, for example,
例如
I have a date that might be interesting to explore.
这里有个“Date”维度比较有意思
So, I'm going to show a filter for the date and
我将显示过滤器
then instead of check boxes, I want to have a single value list.
我不想用复选框 而是用单个值列表
And now I can start to see trends and ask questions.
现在可以看到趋势并提出问题
For example the data in 1999 looks different than the data in 2008.
例如 1999 年的数据和 2008 年的看起来不一样
And so now you can start to say, what was it that caused those changes and
你可以提问 是什么导致这些变化的？
what can I learn from this dataset?
我可以从该数据集中得出什么结论？
&gt;&gt; Right, so now that we're diving deeper with the filters and
—-现在我们已经深入了解了过滤器和其他功能
all that, how would you actually start making this into a dashboard so
你会如何将这些部分变成显示面板
that you can share these interesting stories with others?
从而能够与他人分享这些结果？
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so dashboard is a series of
—-显示面板是指一系列的部分相结合
parts that when combined are greater then the whole, right?
比整体效果更佳
So a number of visualizations that could be combined to tell a different story or
各种可视化图表结合可以讲述不同的故事
show you a different perspective of your data.
或者从不同的角度展示数据
So here I I have a bar chart, but this is geographic data,
这是条形图 这个是地理数据
so it might also be interesting to look at it as a map.
所以当做地图来看 可能也会有意思
So here I have a dimension that shows the country and
这个维度显示的是国家/地区
I'm going to click on a little Show Me section in the corner here that's going
我将点击右上角的“Show Me”部分
to suggest some visualizations and here it's selected a map.
接着系统给出了一些可视化图表 我选择了地图
So if I add this map, it is now showing me where asylum seekers ended up.
如果我添加这个地图 它将显示这些难民留在了哪里
All of the countries that took in asylum seekers are represented by a single dot.
所有接受难民的国家/地区都用一个点表示
But I also want to know how many asylum seekers went to each country.
但是我还想知道有多少难民前往了每个国家/地区
So I might take this number of asylum seekers and drag this onto color.
所以拖动这个“Number of Asylum Seekers”并放到“Color”上
And now, we can start to see where there were some hotspots, so
现在可以看到一些热门国家
it looks like Germany is a hotspot.
似乎德国是热门国家
And actually all of Europe looks kind of interesting, so I'm going to
实际上整个欧洲都值得研究
zoom in on Europe, and now I can start to see a geographic story emerge.
所以我将放大查看欧洲 现在可以看到一个地理图表
Now, there's also a time dimension in this
这个数据集还有一个时间维度
dataset that's interesting to explore.
值得研究
And so one of the things that I could do is I could look at the number
我可以查看难民人数
of asylum seekers and then I could look at the date, okay?
然后查看日期
And see Tableau automatically changed that into a line chart for
Tableau 自动变成了折线图
me, because a line is a really good way to explore dates.
因为这样非常适合研究日期
And now this date actually also comes with a built-in hierarchy.
这个日期实际上还有内置的层级
And what that means is I can see a plus button here and
也就是我可以在这里看到一个加号
that means that I can drill down further to Quarter or to, for example, Month.
意味着我可以继续细分为季度或月份
And I can start to see the data in different ways and
我可以通过不同的方式
from different perspectives.
和以不同的角度查看数据
Now, if I wanted to turn this into a dashboard,
如果我想将这些变成显示面板
I would tap on the new dashboard icon here.
我可以点按新建显示面板图标
And here I have sheets that are in the corner for
旁边是这些表格
me, and I can start dragging those onto my dashboard and if I hover
我可以将这些表格拖到显示面板上 如果将光标悬停在上方
over them I see a little thumbnail that helps me know what I'm looking at.
可以看到缩略图 告诉我正在查看的是什么
So I'm going to drag that sheet here.
将这个表格拖到这里
I'm going to drag the map out on top.
将地图拖到上方
And them I'm going to drag this line chart to the side.
然后将这个折线图拖到这边
Now, I can't quite see everything that's going on, so
无法看清所有内容
I'm going to change this from fixed size to automatic.
所以将尺寸从“Fixed size”改成”Automatic”
And then, they're a couple of things that I want to do here.
还需要执行几项操作
I want to take away these titles, they're not really helping me right now.
取消显示这些标题 它们没什么用
So we'll remove those, and then we'll remove this.
取消这个 然后取消这个
And then I want to, one of the other cool things that you can do with
Tableau 还有一个很酷的功能
Tableau is that you can use visualizations as filters.
可以将可视化图表当做过滤条件
So that's another really interesting thing that you can do with filters.
这是另一个关于过滤条件的有趣功能
So here, we have filters for dates, but we can also filter by country.
这些是日期过滤器 但是我们也可以按国家/地区过滤
So what I can do is I can click on this button to use as a filter.
我可以点击这个“Use as Filter”按钮
And then I can take this filter for
然后使用这个日期过滤器
date and I can apply it to all of the worksheets using this data source, okay?
并应用到所有使用该数据来源的工作表中
And then I'm going to do a simple customization here,
进行简单的自定义
I'm also going to float this.
然后使这个悬浮起来
I'm going to change it to a drop down and then I will resize it.
将其改为下拉列表并重新调整尺寸
And put it on the map here and I'll take this away, okay.
放到地图上 然后删掉这个
And now we have a visualization.
这就是可视化图表了
And if I put that into full screen mode,
如果全屏显示的话
you have this beautiful view where you can start to explore data, right?
就可以看到这个很美观的数据图表 你可以开始探索这些数据了
So now I can see what's happening in France in 2008 versus 2014,
例如 我可以查看 2008 年与 2014 年
for example, right?
法国的状况
And you can start really digging in and asking questions and
你可以通过各种方式探索这些数据
exploring in a very rich way.
并开始提出问题
&gt;&gt; Great, that was really cool, I like that.
—-太棒了 我很喜欢
Okay, so these are dashboards, but
这些就是显示面板
Tableau also let's you build stories, right?
Tableau 还可以帮助我们构建故事 对吧？
So, what' s the difference between a story and a dashboard and
故事和显示面板有何区别
when would you use one rather the other?
你会在什么场合使用故事或显示面板？
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's a great question and
—-问的好
I like to think of it as a story has a narrative and it has a sequence.
我认为故事有叙述内容并且有一定的顺序
You want people to understand the information in a particular order.
你希望人们按照特定的顺序了解信息
So with a dashboard it gives you an overview of what's going on.
显示面板给出了所发生状况的概览
So I think of it kind of like you just show up at the food track and
就像你来到了食品站
there's the menu on the side and
旁边有个菜单
you want a picture of what all the different options are.
你想要看看都有什么食物
And maybe you're only interested in appetizers right now.
或许你目前只对开胃食品感兴趣
It's really easy for you to find that appetizer section and
你很容易找到开胃食品部分
just get something small.
并获得少量食物
A story on the other hand is more like a Comic book.
故事更像漫画书
You really want to understand the history and context and
你非常想要了解整个历史和背景
understand how you came to a particular conclusion.
想知道你如何得出了特定的结论
So, you can also build stories in Tableau, so
你也可以在 Tableau 中构建故事
I'm going to click on the new story button.
我将点击“New Story”按钮
And maybe I want to tell the story of how I arrived at a particular insight.
我可以讲述我是如何得出特定见解的
So here I can take the sheets and dashboards and
我可以利用这些表格和显示面板
combine them into stories.
将它们组合成故事
So maybe I start with this sheet and I add it here and I add a caption.
从这个表格开始 将其添加到这里并添加一个标题
This is the first part of my story and then I can take another sheet and
“This is the first part of my story”然后再拿一个表格
I can add a new story point and add a caption.
添加一个新的故事点并添加标题
Here's where I found this insight.
“Here's where I found this insight”
And you can also add dashboards as well, right?
你也可以添加显示面板
And in this case we're also going to move this, change this to automatic so
这里也将这个改成“Automatic”
I can see everything that's going on.
这样可以看清所有内容
And when we go to our story we can start by sharing the first part of the story
回到我们的故事 我们可以先分享故事的第一部分
and then move people along in sequence, so that they understand your insights.
然后按顺序查看 使他人能够理解你的见解